If I could just have everybody's attention real quick.
各位 注意了
Um,on this wonderful occasion - Our daughter leaving tomorrow for college...
在此良辰美景 我家闺女明天要去上大学了
If I could get everyone to raise their glass
请大家举杯
as I quote from one of our nation's great fathers - Jefferson.
让我引用我国一位伟大父亲Jefferson
George jefferson.
George jefferson的话
"i never dreamed that one of my own "would be going off to a university,"but here I stand,
我从没想过我的孩子会上大学 但我站在这
a proud black man,knowing that all those hours I put in at the dry cleaner
作为一个骄傲的黑人 生活都奉献给干洗店
-phil. - Not now,weezie.
- Phil - 嘘
- Where was i? - Quoting that president.
- 说到哪了 - 引用那个总统的话
Okay,if she's the future of america,we should start using chinese money now.
如果她是美国的未来 现在咱开始用人民币吧
We already are.
已经在用了
My arm is tired.To haley.
我胳膊都酸了 敬Haley
To haley!
敬Haley
And before everyone puts their glasses down,uh,uh,we're also very proud of lily.
大家放杯前 我们同样为Lily骄傲
Tomorrow is her first day of kindergarten.
明天是她第一天上幼儿园
- To lily. - Oh,lily.
- 敬Lily - Lily
And you'll be impressed to know that she's gonna be one of the smartest girls there.
你会为她成为最聪明的女孩而惊叹
- Lily,sweetie,what's the square root of 64? - 8.
- Lily 宝贝 64的平方根是多少 - 8
Nice trick.
小儿科
- Hey,lily,what's the square root of this potato? - 8.
- Lily 这个土豆的平方根是多少 - 8
Congratulations.You have a parrot.
恭喜你 会鹦鹉学舌了
We couldn't even get through the toast to haley before you pulled focus to lily.
还没敬完Haley 你就把注意力转移到Lily了
Oh,come on.It's-it's a big day for both of them.Huh?
哎呦 对她们俩都是大日子
Haley going to college is a miracle.
Haley能上大学是个奇迹
Lily going to kindergarten is the law.
Lily上幼儿园是法律
Well,haley and lily aren't the only ones starting school.
Haley和Lily不是唯一去上学的人
My mom and jay are going to parenting class.
我妈和Jay也要去上亲子班
We're doing it for the baby.
我们是为了宝宝
Not this baby.That baby.
不是小宝宝 那个大宝宝
Manny doesn't believe that we know what we're doing.
Manny认为我们不知道自己在干嘛
A couple of new hairs under his arm,and now he thinks he knows more than his own mother.
腋下长了缕新毛 就觉得自己懂得比亲妈还多
I know not to embarrass my son as he stands on the threshold of manhood.
我儿子蜕变为男人的开始 我可不会让他尴尬
I don't know why I have to go to this thing.In case you've forgotten,I raised two kids.
我不知道为啥我要上这课 别忘了我养大了俩孩子
- Stop pulling my hair. - Stop twisting my nipple.
- 别抓我头发 - 别拧我咪咪
Shut up.Shut up.
闭嘴
Why look at me?
看我干嘛
It was their mother's fault.I was barely around.
那是他们妈妈的错 我很少在家
No!
不要
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=-Proudly Presents
-=伊甸园美剧 http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=伊甸园字幕站 http://ytet.org=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=-Sync: YTET-楳直直直
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=- 翻译: 豆大福 July 旖旎 校对: 安坠崖 时间轴:YTET-青木木木
Modern Family Season 04 Episode 02
摩登家庭 第四季 第二集
Haley,this is,like,the third bag of makeup and hair care products.
Haley 这是第三袋洗护用品了吧
Dad,if you want me to get good grades,I have to look cute.
老爸 如果要得高分 我得秀色可餐
- Don't say a word. - No.No.
- 啥也别说 - 不说
- I agree with that premise. - Thank you.
- 我同意你的假设 - 谢谢
Wait.
等等
Yeah,thank you.
好了 谢谢
Claire.
Claire
In haley's stuff,a box of condoms.
Haley的行李里有盒套套
Yeah.Um,I-I bought those for her.
对 我给她买的
What?
什么
Why don't you just buy her some fishnet stockings and a nurse's outfit?
你怎么不给她买网袜和护士制服
Not that that's my thing.
我没说那是我的菜
That just popped into my head.
就这么脱口而出了
Honey,she's an adult,and she's going to college.
亲 她是成人了 要去上大学
I want to be realistic.I don't want her to get caught unprepared.
我想现实一点 不想让她毫无准备
24 times?What,are you buying her a 4-year supply?
24次 你给她买的四年的量吗
Please.Phil,that would've lasted me and my college boyfriend,like,a long...
拜托 Phil 这点量对我和大学的男朋友...
Okay,we gotta hit the road.
好了 该出发了
Give your sister a hug good-bye.
给你姐姐一个告别拥抱
- Don't dork up our room. -Don't slut up your college.
- 别让卧室变书房 - 别在大学里放荡
Seriously,though,don't study too hard,okay?
说真的 别太努力学习好吗
I'm totally going to have fun.
我会找点乐子的
I'm iceland in the mock u.n.
我是模拟联合国里的冰岛
Mom,we're gonna lose her.
妈妈 我们会失去她的
I am doing my best.
我尽力了
Luke,come say good-bye to your sister.
Luke 来和你姐姐道别
I'm right here.
我在这呢
Bye,haley.Have fun.
再见 Haley 玩得开心
Don't drink too much beer and shots of tequila.
别喝太多啤酒和龙舌兰
Why are you wearing that mask?
你为什么带着面具
Uh,I like it.
我喜欢
He doesn't want you to see him cry.
他不想让你看到他哭
He's literally masking his emotions.
他遮住的是情感
- no! - That's so sweet.
- 没有 - 好感人
Come here.
过来
It's not sweet.I'm an evil cyborg.
不感人 我是邪恶的半机械人
Half my face was burned off in an industrial accident,
工厂事故烧掉了我半边脸
and the mask is hiding the servos that control my mouth.
面具是为了掩饰控制嘴的伺服系统
Yes,I am sad haley is leaving,but I'm gonna be okay knowing I've done everything I can
是的 我为Haley的离开而伤心 但没事的
to get her set up and prepared and off on the right foot.
我已经为她整装出发尽了力
Not me.
我有事
When we're standing in her dorm room saying good-bye,
在她宿舍和她道别
it's gonna be one of the most emotional moments of my life.
会是我这辈子最伤感的时刻之一
I'm gonna cry harder than the first time I saw "air bud"...
会比第一次看"神犬也疯狂"哭得还凶
Especially when I give her this.
尤其是当我把这个给她
"phil's-osophy.
Phil的哲学
A hardbound collection of all the life lessons I've learned,such as...
一本精装书 有我学到的所有人生课 例如...
"always look people in the eye,"even if they're blind.
直视别人的眼睛 即使他们是盲人
Just say,'i'm looking you in the eye.
告诉他 我在看着你的眼睛
'" or...
还有...
"if you get pulled over for speeding,tell the policeman your spouse has diarrhea.
如果超速被抓 告诉警察你家那口子拉肚子
" Phil's-osophy.
Phil的哲学
Look how much fun you're gonna have here,lily.
Lily 看这多有意思
So many great toys to play with,and you're gonna make so many new friends.
好多玩具玩 还能交到新朋友
Oh,I wish I was in kindergarten again.
真希望再上一次幼儿园
Oh,not me.Did I ever tell you about david anthony?
我可不想 我跟你说过David Anthony吗
He used to call me "cam the ham.
他叫我火腿Cam
" Okay,lily's day.
好了 今天是Lily的大日子
Yeah,you're right.You know what?It's gonna be a great day.
你说得对 今天是个大日子
I'm just saying,it's difficult to grow up with a name that rhymes with "ham.
我只是说 名字跟火腿谐音是成长的阴影
" Hello?Mitch?Witch.Twitch.Bitch.Elaine stritch.
嘿 Mitch 女巫 抽筋 贱人 Elaine Stritch
What?
什么
Not all bullies are straight.
不是所有恶霸都是直男
Okay,parents.
好了 家长们
We'll see you at 12:00.
12点见了
All right.
好吧
This is when the crying starts.
哭点到了
Does it ever stop?
就没停过吧
Come on,cam.
好了 Cam
Okay.You know what,lily,sweetie?
Lily宝贝儿
I know this is gonna be difficult
我知道这很难
- bye! - Okay.
- 再见 - 好吧
That was a knife to the heart.
简直是一把利刃直插心口
No,it's...it's a good thing.Come on.
不 这是好事 走吧
Oh,you know what?She forgot her snack.
她忘了拿点心
Where'd she go?
她去哪了
That hurts!That hurts!
好疼
Oh,lily,honey!
Lily宝宝
Sweetheart,come here.Come here.
宝贝儿 过来
If you ever put your hands on my daughter again,
如果你再敢碰我女儿
I will string you up by your feet,run you up the flagpole,and let the birds peck out your eyes
我会把你的脚拧成绳 把你升上旗杆 让鸟来啄你眼睛
You understand?
明白吗
Mr.Tucker,put that boy down!
Tucker先生 放下那个男孩
He pulled my daughter's hair.
他扯我闺女的头发
Please apologize to connor for using your hands instead of your words.
请你对动手不动口向Connor道歉
Sorry,little fella.
对不住 小伙子
- I would like to see you in my office. - Right.
- 我办公室见 - 好吧
- Now,please. - Me,too?
- 现在 - 我也去啊
Caw!Caw!
嘎 嘎
Stop it.Leave him alone.
停 别弄他了
Mr.Tucker,what happened out there was unacceptable.
Tucker先生 刚才发生的事是不允许的
I agree.Is this kindergarten or "the hunger games"?
我同意 这是幼儿园还是饥饿游戏
I'm speaking of your behavior.
我在说你的行为
We've never had an incident like this,and now we've had one on the first day,
我们从没遇过这样的事 现在第一天就出了幺蛾子
before circle time.
在上课前
What the fudge were you thinking?
你们脑子里想的什么
Now the boy's parents are coming in,and trust me,they're mad as hello kitty.
现在男孩的家长正在过来 他们可不喜欢男同
Oh,you told his parents on us?
你告诉他家长了啊
That is-that is so not cool.
太不和谐了
Well,I'm sure once they hear what their boy did,they will be understanding.
知道他们儿子干了啥 他们会理解的
All right,whoever made our son cry has messed with the wrong moms.
谁把我儿子弄哭 肯定惹错人了
Lesbians.
女同志
While often lumped together,gay men and lesbians have less in common than one might think.
虽然经常放在一起说 但男女同志没什么共同之处
Like in the venn diagram of sexual identity,you have gay men...
在性身份的维恩图解中 男同
And straight men.
和直男
Both the same gender.
是同一性别
Then you have gay men...
然后男同
And straight women.
和直女
Both attracted to the same gender.
都被同一性别吸引
But gay men and lesbians?
但男同和女同呢
Nothing.
啥都没有
I am so sorry we have to meet like this,
很抱歉我们要这样见面
but I'm sure you can understand,as parents,the instinct to protect your child.
但我想你们能了解 作为父母 有保护孩子的本能
Yeah,it's what makes me want to punch you in the neck right now.
所以我现在想打断你的脖子
I see where your son gets all of his aggression.
我知道你儿子为啥好斗了
Okay,let's all take a time-out.
好了 都停下
That's a good idea.
好主意
- This is getting a little heated.Right? - Yeah,pam,
- 有点升级了是吧 - 是啊 Pam
we don't want another incident like at the lumberyard.
可别再像上次木场那件事
Oh,my god.You guys go to the lumberyard,too?
太巧了 你们也去Lumberyard(木场)
D - I didn't know they had a ladies' night.
原来那儿还有"女同之夜"
Not the bar,sally.
我们说的不是酒吧 Sally
Okay,you know what?
好了 你知道吗
He's trying to be nice,and you just called him "sally.
人家不断示好 你却叫人家"Sally"
" Yeah,you're not being very helpful,peppermint patty.
就是 你也没帮上啥忙 薄荷小饼妞儿
Okay.Let's just stick to our actual names.
好了 咱们别乱取绰号了
Enough.
别吵了
I'm gonna give you a little homework assignment.
我给你们布置一个家庭作业
I want you and your kids to have a family playdate.
你们两个家庭来一次聚会
Maybe if the four of you can get along,you can set a better example for your children.
到时你们四个好好相处 给孩子们做个榜样
- I think that's a wonderful idea.Pam? - Fine.
- 这主意太棒了 Pam - 行
- cam?
- Cam - 好
We'll host,obviously.
在我们家搞吧 明摆的事
"obviously"?
明摆的事
Well,I assume you have an unfinished woodworking project at your house.
你家估计还堆着没做完的木工活呢
You've got a lot of nerve.
你还真敢说啊
Yeah,and you've got half a canoe in our living room.
咱家客厅确实有半个独木舟
I look forward to your frittata.
准备去吃你做的煎蛋饼
Why,are you visiting us in 2008?
为啥 你以为现在2008年么
- Oh,my god. - Okay,thanks.
- 天呐 - 谢谢
Baby for you.
给你的娃
You have some explaining to do.
你不得解释解释娃为啥是黑皮肤的
I'm so sorry that you had to find out like this,jay.
很抱歉你现在才发现
Wow,you two are really far along.
哇 你这怀了好久了吧
We're,uh,we're still in our first trimester.
我们还是头三个月
Ay,that's nice.
挺好啊
Yeah,we've been trying to get pregnant for ages.
是啊 我们尝试好久了才怀上
She's latina.You just gotta look at her funny.
她是拉丁美洲女人 看着就会好笑
Okay,now that everyone has their doll,let's talk about swaddling.
好 现在人手一娃 我们讲讲怎样包娃娃
Now you want to start by turning one corner of the blanket toward you,
大家先把毯子一角朝向自己
like a diamond,and folding the top down,like this.
呈菱形 然后向下折这个角 像这样
I think they made a mistake at the hospital.
医院可能搞错咱俩的娃了
Tough room.
太没幽默细胞了
Now we are going to pull the other corner 'round,
接着把另一角折过来
and tuck it in nice and snug like a burrito.
掖好它 像个玉米卷 又美又舒服
Done!I win.
弄好了 我赢啦
It's not a race.
咱们不是比赛
You're darn right.It wasn't even close.
你太对了 差得远呢
Okay,it's good,but it's a little tight.
挺好的 但是有点紧
It's a burrito.You don't want the meat to fall out.
是玉米卷啊 太松肉会掉出来
Here.And try like this.
试试这样
And see?
看
Now your baby can breathe.
这样宝宝才能呼吸
I wrapped my son with one hand while driving a stick.
姐可是一手开车一手包娃的
I think I know how to keep a baby safe.
我知道咋样让娃安全
Man,I love being back in the dorms.
又回到宿舍了 爱死了
It's like I never left.
好像从没离开过啊
Throw up a david copperfield poster,this could be my room.
贴张大卫・科波菲尔的海报 这简直就是我的房间了
Honey,haley and I have to go fill out some paperwork.
亲爱的 Haley和我得去填些表
Why don't you throw the linens on the bed?
你铺下床单吧
Okay.
好
- Oh,my god.What is that shirt? - Pretty sweet,huh?
- 天呐 你穿的神马T恤 - 很可爱 是吧
"haley dunphy moving co." mm.see?'cause we're moving you here and here.
"Haley Dunphy搬家公司" 看到吗 因为我们帮你搬家到这里
And also...Here.
当然 还有心里...
Man,you used to love it when we swung you like that.
你小时候很喜欢拉着我们的手荡秋千
I bet we could still do it.
我们现在还是可以的哦
- Yeah! - Yeah.
- 耶
Oh,no,no.No,no,no,no,no.Don't you dare pick me up!
不不不不不不 千万别来拉我
And take that shirt off.
把这T恤脱掉
What?Why?
神马 为啥
It's cute!
很好看啊
It's not cute!
不好看
Do you see what's happening out there?
你没看到外面是神马情况吗
People are walking around and judging each other.
大家都互相评头论足的
No,they're not.
没有啊
Oh,really?You didn't see the way muffin top across the hall was looking at me?
是吗 你刚没看到对面人看我的眼神吗
People can be cruel.
人们可以很邪恶的
So take it off.
脱掉它
Fine.
好吧
Oh,my god!Put on a shirt!
天呐 赶快穿上
I don't know what you want from me!
你到底要我怎样
"you only get one chance at a first impression.
给别人留下第一印象只有一次机会
I suggest julia child,because it's easy to do.
我推荐模仿食神Julia Child 因为很简单
" "save the giblets.
"留着内脏"
" Time to go to the beach!
去海滩喽
You're gonna go to the beach with a dog?
你要带狗狗去海滩吗
- That dog on the beach. - I don't know what I did to deserve this.
- 小狗狗去海滩 - 这么可爱的孩子 我真是三生修来的
Yeah.
就是
I want to show connor my toys.
我想给Connor看我的玩具
Oh,okay.You do that,sweetie.
好 去吧 宝贝
Hey,connor,uh,no hair pulling.
Connor 别扯她头发哦
Thank you for that.
谢谢你提醒他这个
Okay,we have an assortment of spring rolls here.
我准备了各种春卷
All vegetarian,of course.
都是素的
Oh,'cause I'm a lesbian,i'm automatically a vegetarian?
因为我是拉拉 就一定吃素了
Well,I saw it on "the l word." I assume they have consultants.
我可是在"拉字至上"看到的 人家肯定研究过的
I'm just saying it's an offensive stereotype.
我只想说这是个不敬的说法
Okay,pam,you are a vegetarian.
好了 Pam 你确实吃素
Knock it off.
得了吧
Worked out.
对了吧
Yeah.So glad that we are doing this.
真高兴咱们能这样一聚
Yeah.Yeah,me,too.
是啊 是啊
Yeah.Yeah.I mean,we're the only gay parents in the class.
对啊 我们可是班上仅有的同志父母
Yeah,we should be supporting one another.
是啊 我们应该互相支持
I mean,we have so much in common.
我们有这么多共同点
Exactly.
就是
So...
然后...
Tell us about yourselves.
介绍下自己吧
I'm an environmental lawyer.
我是个环境律师
Uh,and I'm a homemaker.
我是家庭煮夫
And-and,uh,and what do you do?
你们是做什么的呢
I'm a financial consultant.
我是金融顾问
I'm a contractor.
我是承包商
You thought I was a p.e.Teacher?
你以为我是体育老师
Well,figured.
我猜的
Hey,I have a question real quick.
我有个小问题
How do you guys get the car seat on the motorcycle?
你们怎么把小孩座位装到摩托车上的
Uh,you know,connor is having a birthday next week.
Connor下周有个生日会
Maybe lily would like to come.
不知道Lily想不想来
Oh,she would love that.
她肯定很想去的
Oh,great.Are you guys having a clown?
太好了 你们要请个小丑么
Oh,god,no.I hate clowns they're so creepy.
神啊 我讨厌小丑 很恐怖
Maybe you just don't like them because they wear makeup.
你是因为小丑会化妆才不喜欢他们的
You know what?I'm out.
得 不玩儿了
- Okay. - pam.
- 好嘞 - Pam
Connor,we're leaving!
Connor 咱们准备走了
- Pam!- You-you don't understand.Cam used to be a clown.
Pam你不知道 Cam过去是扮小丑的
"used to be"?Once a clown,always a clown.
"过去" 一时小丑 一世小丑
God!Not now!Not now!
上帝啊不是说这些的时候
- Connor,let's go. - pam.
- Connor 咱走了 - Pam
What?
怎么了
- Why is this door locked? - Let me,please.
- 门怎么是锁的 - 让我来
Lily,open this door right now.
Lily 马上把门打开
Okay.
行了
- I'm not hearing anything. - I'm sure they're fine.
- 里面没声音 - 肯定没事的
Oh,how are you sure?
你怎么肯定
- Connor! - Lily!
- Connor - Lily
Make the water comfortably warm 90 to 100 degrees max.
水温控制在华氏90到100度之间
And never leave the tub unsupervised.
视线不能离开浴盆
Is there something you two want to share with the class?
你们俩有什么要跟大家分享的吗
No.It's dirty.
没有 很黄的
Excuse me.
不好意思
We're trying to arn here.
我们还想学东西呢
Don't worry so much.
不用太担心
Babies are tougher than you think.
小孩没你想的那么矜贵
When I was 5 years old,my babysitter was a goat.
我5岁时 我的保姆是只山羊
What?
神马
Ay,please.You know about lupe.
得了吧 你知道Lupe的
You never said she was a goat.
你没说过她是山羊啊
You know,it's great that we have a couple of experienced parents in the class.
班里有一对有经验的父母是好事
Perhaps you can share some of your wisdom with the rest of us.
你们可以跟大家分享下经验
Absolutely.It's not rocket science.
当然可以 又不是造火箭
It's babies.They're hungry,you feed 'em.
只是娃娃而已 饿了给喂吃的就行
They're teething,you give 'em some scotch.
要是磨牙 就给灌点酒
- Scotch? - Really?Are you serious?
- 酒 - 真的吗 不是开玩笑
What?
怎么了
So we left.
所以我们就走了
I didn't need a lecture from mary poppins.
我可不用Mary Poppins来给我上课
And I was suddenly in a mood for a burrito.
我突然想吃玉米煎饼
I'd like admission to your student body.
让我摸摸你保持的这么好的身材
Oh,my goodness!I am so sorry.I thought you were my wife.
天啊太抱歉了 我以为你是我老婆
What's going on?
怎么了
- He grabbed me and said - I thought she was my wife.
- 他捏我 - 我以为她是我老婆
My wife works out a lot.
我老婆经常健身的
dad?
老爸
How'd he grab you?
他怎么捏你的
He squeezed my butt.
他捏了我的屁股
- He what? - Phil!
- 什么 - Phil
I thought it was you!
我以为是你
Believe me,sir.I'm a respected realtor.
相信我 先生 我是个受尊敬的房产经纪人
This is an innocent mistake.
刚才是无心之过
Honey,turn around and show him your-your butt.
亲爱的 转过身给他看你的屁屁
It-it's uncanny.
绝对超乎你想象
Dad.I am very normal.
老爸 我可是个正常人
Please do not judge me based on them.
千万别把我想得跟他们一样
Are those your my little pony sheets?
这是你的彩虹小马床单
What?No!
什么不
I ordered them online.
我网购的
They must've sent the wrong ones.I'm very sorry.
卖家肯定发错货了 非常抱歉
That's what was in the box.
没验货直接就拿出来了
Okay.Uh,for the record,I am a respected realtor.
重申一下 我是个受尊敬的房产经纪人
Those are not my condoms.
那不是我的套套
She bought 'em.
她买的
Oh,my god.
额滴神
Apparently,that's what people do these days - Buy condoms for their kids.
现在家长给孩子买套套很普遍
When I went to college,my parents bought me a bicycle helmet.
我上大学时 爸妈给我买的是自行车头盔
That was their idea of safety.
他们对安全措施的定义
Certainly didn't need condoms.
显然不是套套
Mm,not if you were wearing a bike helmet around campus,you didn't.
你要是真如他们所想成天骑单车转悠 当然不需要套套
Am I right?
是吧
Why don't we let you guys finish,and we'll come back later?
你们先拾掇吧 我们一会儿回来
- Okay.
- 好
Yeah.Yeah.Yep.Yeah.Yeah,that sounds good.
是的 很好 是啊 好主意
See you on parents weekend!
家长活动日再见咯
They seem nice.
他们瞅着挺好的哈
- Guys... - I know.
- 爸妈... - 了解
I know.Look,we need to reorganize a little.
了解 咱得重新整顿下
Your dad will go out and get us some new sheets.
你爸去给你买新床单
You and I can hang up all the pictures on the walls.
咋俩来把照片挂墙上
You know what?I think it's best if you guys get going.
你们最好还是回去吧
But we-we wanted to help you,sweetie.
可是我们想帮你呀 宝贝儿
No,I got it.
不用 我自己能行
W - what if you wanna move the furniture around?
要是你想挪挪家具呢
And we were gonna take you to dinner before we left.
走前我们仨一块儿吃个晚饭吧
I like the furniture where it is,and I'm not hungry.So...
家具就这样挺好 我也不饿 所以...
- Okay.
- 好吧 - 好
Um,well,uh,before we leave,I wanted to give you a little present.
临别前给你个小礼物
It's actually not a little present.
其实也不算啥小礼物啦
It's probably the best present you're ever gonna get.
可能是你这辈子得到的最好的礼物哦
It's a collection of all the things I've learned - thanks.
- 这是我的人生经验选集 - 谢啦
Attention.Dorm meeting in the common room.
请注意 到公共休息室参加寝室会议
Okay,so...
好了
I better go.
我要开会了
- I know. - Okay.
- 是啊 - 好的
Okay,come here.That's my girl.
到妈这儿来 宝贝闺女
- Let me get in there. - Okay.
- 爸也抱一下 - 好
All right.
去吧
- bye! - bye.
- 拜
"the most amazing things that can happen to a human being "
"降低期望值
will happen to you if you just lower your expectations.
你就会得到众所期待的美好事物"
" Oh,they've got something over the hole.
锁眼被他们挡住了
- Lily! - Connor!
- Lily - Connor
We can't see anything from outside.
从外面啥也瞧不见
The curtains are closed.
窗帘拉严实了
Open up,connor!
开门 Connor
We'll let you have a hot dog!
外头有热狗吃
What if something happened to them?
他们出事了可怎么办
What kind of hazards do you keep in there?
屋子里有哪些危险物品
Well,let's see.That's where we keep our gun collection,our abandoned refrigerator,
我想想哈 有枪支 废弃冰箱
and our chocolate-covered hypodermic needles.
还有裹着巧克力的皮下注射针头
Why are gay men always so sarcastic?
基佬为毛都爱冷嘲热讽
- It's my coping mechanism! - Okay,that's it!
- 这是我的应对机制 - 别吵吵了
lily,connor,if you can hear me,back away from the door.I'm gonna break it down.
Lily Connor 能听见不 离门远点 我要撞门了
- I'll help you. - I don't want connor to go!
- 我帮你 - 我不想Connor走
I wanna stay!
我想呆在这儿
Oh,thank god they're alive!
上帝保佑 他们还活着
I love him!
我爱他
No,you love the idea of him.Now open this door,sweetie.
不 你只是爱他的小聪明 快开门 亲爱的
Can we really have hot dogs?
开门真的给我们热狗吃吗
Yes,we promise.
真的 我们保证
Come here,sweetheart.
快过来 小宝贝
If you ask me...
说起来...
Sometimes we focus too much on our differences.
有时我们过于关注男女同志的差异
There's one thing that all parents have in common.
却忽略了彼此最大的共同点
When it comes to the safety and well-being of our children,we're all a little bit nuts.
当涉及孩子的幸福安康时 我们都有点神经质
You have dainty little hands,just like your daughter.
你跟你女儿一样十指芊芊
You have boots like my dad.
你跟我爸一样大脚丫子
I'm not saying that the goat put me to sleep or brushed my teeth.
我又没说那山羊哄我睡觉 给我刷牙
It just stayed outside my bedroom window and scared all the strangers away.
它只是呆在我卧室窗外吓跑怪蜀黍
Well,I'm not gonna lie.I'm a little disappointed.
我可不想掩饰 我有点失望
Hey,kid!
嘿 孩子
Jay,mom,how was class?
Jay 妈 课上得如何
It was great.
超好
It was very educating and - And now we know everything about the baby,no?
学到很多东西 现在我们了解有关宝宝的一切 是吧
Interesting,because your teacher called,and you forgot your sunglasses when you left...
是吗 老师打给我说你把太阳镜落下了...
Three hours early.
三小时前打的
Ay,manny,don't be mad.
Manny 别生气
I'm not mad.Just disappointed.
我不生气 只是失望
I hate this.I prefer when he screams.
我讨厌这样 我宁愿他对我尖叫
Manny,it's no big deal.
Manny 这没什么大不了的
They weren't telling us anything we didn't already know.
他们教的我们都懂
We're going to have a baby.
宝宝就快出生了
Am I the only one who's terrified?
难道只有我一个人在害怕吗
But why?
为什么呀
why are you so terrified?
你为什么那么害怕呢
What if it doesn't know not to pick up knives or stick its finger in an electric socket?
万一宝宝不小心玩刀子 或者把手指伸进插座孔怎么办
You were pretty lax,mom.
你可是个马大哈呀 妈
I was the one who told you to turn the pot handles towards the stove so I couldn't reach them.
还是我提醒你的 把壶柄转向炉子我才抓不着
Manny,I didn't worry about those things because you worried for the both of us.
Manny 我是不太管事 因为有你帮我们俩操心嘛
What if this baby doesn't think things through?
万一宝宝不像我这么周全谨慎呢
It's part jay.
有Jay的遗传啊
No offense taken.
童言无忌啦
If the baby's different,we'll be different.
如果宝宝不像你这样 我们也不会像现在这样
When you were growing up,you had to be  the man of the house and the kid.
你的成长过程中 既是家中的男子汉又只是个孩子
Now I'm here.
现在有我了
You just have to be the kid.
你只要作个孩子就行了
I'm not gonna let anything happen to the baby,
我不会让宝宝出什么事的
just like I'm not ever gonna let anything happen to you.
就像我永远不会让你出事一样
Okay?
好吗
Okay.
好
That is a load off.
真是如释重负
Although you forgot to pick me up last week after tango class.
但是上周你们上完探戈课忘了来接我哈
We didn't forget.We were just ten minutes late.
没忘 迟到10分钟而已
Ten minutes is a long time in a sketchy neighborhood.
让小孩独自 在陌生社区呆10分钟那么久
Please.It was between a gymboree and a pottery barn.
得了 旁边就是"金宝贝"童装店 和"陶瓷仓库"家居城
"dance until your feet hurt.
"热舞到脚软"
"sing until your lungs hurt.
"K歌到肺疼"
Act until you're william hurt.
"狂演舞台剧到莎翁也倾倒"
" How you doing?Are you okay?
"你咋样还好吧"
Yeah.No,I'm.I'm-i'm-i'm good.You?
挺好 不 我 我很好 你呢
Fine.Yeah.
我挺好啊
Great.
不错
"Take a lesson from parakeets.
"学学长尾小鹦鹉"
"If you're ever feeling lonely,just eat in front of a mirror."
"觉得孤单的话 对镜作伴吃饭吧"
"never be afraid to reach for the stars,"
"别不敢上天摘星星"
because even if you fall,you'll always be wearing a parent-chute.
"就算跌下来 父母牌保护伞永远相伴"
"   tm."
"独家专利"
haley.Hi,honey.You okay?
Haley 亲爱的 你还好吗
Yeah.Where are you guys?
挺好 你们到哪儿了
Almost home,honey.
快到家了 亲爱的
Dad,I really like that book.
爸 我很喜欢你给我的书
You do?
真哒
Sweetheart,is everything okay?
宝贝儿 一切都好吗
Yeah,I just wanted to say thank you for everything,you know,today and stuff.
当然 我想说谢谢你们 今天和以往为我做的一切
- O- of course.Of course.- Sure.
- 一家人客气啥 - 就是
If-if you need anything at all...You just call us.
如果你还需要什么...给我们来电话
I'll probably need some more condoms soon.
可能我很快就需要更多套套
Not funny.
不好笑哈
I'm sending you some care bear sheets.
我会给你寄爱心熊床单的
Anyway,I should probably get going.We have orientation at 7:00 a.m.
我得挂了 明早7点要参加新生交流会
G - good luck with that,sweetie.
祝你好运 甜心
I love you,guys.
我爱你们
We love you,too,honey.
我们也爱你 宝贝儿
So,so much.
非常非常爱
- bye. - Bye,haley.
- 拜 - 拜 Haley
I'll miss you.
我会想你们的
"marry someone who looks sexy while disappointed.
"娶个沮丧的时候看起来性感的妞"
" see?
懂吗
"older black ladies make the best iced tea.
"年长的黑人女性最会做冰茶"
" "success is 1% inspiration,"98% perspiration,and 2% attention to detail.
" 成功源自1%的灵感 98%的努力和2%对细节的关注"
" "you can tell a lot about a person from his biography.
"你可以通过一个人的自传了解他"
" "watch a sunrise at least once a day.
"每天至少看一次日出"
" "if you love something,set it free,unless it's a tiger.
"如果你爱着什么 给它自由 老虎除外"
" "if you're ever in jam,"a crayon scrunched up under your nose makes a good pretend mustache.
"堵车的时候 撅起嘴在鼻子下夹只蜡笔 就有一撇假胡子了"
" "when life gives you lemonade,"make lemons.
"生活给你柠檬汽水 就把它变成柠檬"
Life will be all like,'what?
生活会惊呼"搞什么飞机"
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=-Proudly Presents
-------------------------- 本论坛字幕仅翻译交流学习之用 禁止任何商业用途否则后果自负 --------------------------
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=-Sync: YTET-楳直直直
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=- 翻译: 豆大福 July 旖旎 校对: 安坠崖 时间轴:YTET-青木木木
Modern Family Season 04 Episode 02
摩登家庭 第四季 第二集 完